Council on Foreign Relations Records: Studies Department Series, 1918-2004: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Council on Foreign Relations Records: Studies Department Series
1918-2004
MC104.3
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections. Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Public Policy Papers. 65 Olden Street Princeton, New Jersey 08540 USA
134.62 linear feet in 323 boxes
Council on Foreign Relations
The Council on Foreign Relations is a nonprofit, nonpartisan research and national membership organization dedicated to promoting improved understanding of international affairs and to contributing ideas to United States foreign policy. The Studies Department Series documents the planning and execution of the various study groups (including discussion groups, current issue review groups, seminars, workshops and conferences) and projects.
The Council on Foreign Relations (the Council) is a nonprofit, nonpartisan research and national membership organization dedicated to promoting improved understanding of international affairs and to contributing ideas to United States foreign policy. The Council has had a large impact in the development of twentieth century United States foreign policy. Its membership has historically been drawn from those in business, government and academia recognized as the nation’s opinion leaders in international relations; membership is by invitation only. The Council’s basic constituency is its members, but it also reaches out to a wider audience through its publications, Committees on Foreign Relations, Corporate Program, and media efforts, so as to contribute to the national dialogue on foreign policy.
The Studies Department spearheads the Council on Foreign Relation's efforts to promote informed discussion on issues shaping the international agenda and defines the Council's function as a foreign policy research organization. This "think tank" has played a vital role in the Council since its incorporation in the 1920s. The department includes a large number of scholars and research associates who engage each other, Council members, and non-affiliated individuals in research on topics and regions related to United States foreign policy, which historically have included topics such as international trade, arms control, and economic development, and regions such as the former Soviet Union, the Middle East, and Latin America, to name a few. The Studies program produces articles, books, policy reports and papers to disseminate the research undertaken by staff and members.
For a fuller history on the Council on Foreign Relations, see the finding aid for the Council on Foreign Relations Records located at http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/gb19f5814, Peter Grose’s Continuing the Inquiry: The Council on Foreign Relations from 1921-1996, located at http://www.cfr.org/about/history/cfr/ and Michael Wala’s The Council on Foreign Relations and American Foreign Policy in the Early Cold War (Providence: Berghahn Books, 1994).
The Studies Department Series documents the planning and execution of the various study groups (including discussion groups, current issue review groups, seminars, workshops and conferences) and projects. Documents in this series reflect the administration of the Studies Department (mainly through correspondence and subject files), the records of the groups themselves (through correspondence, background papers, meeting minutes and final reports), and the subject files and correspondence of major players in the Council’s Studies Department from the 1940s onward.
Organized into the following subseries:
All Council on Foreign Relations records are closed for 25 years after the date of their creation.
The Council on Foreign Relations Studies Department Records form part of the The Council on Foreign Relations Records (collection MC104). A Finding Aid for the entire collection is available online: Council on Foreign Relations Records Finding Aid.
The Meetings Records of the Council on Foreign Relations are described in a separate finding aid: Council on Foreign Relations Meetings Finding Aid.
Digital sound recordings of some Council meetings are available online. The digital recordings of meeting are described in a separate finding aid: Council on Foreign Relations Digital Sound Recordings Finding Aid.
The collection was deposited at the Library in 1998. Title and custody of the collection were formally transferred to Princeton in 2002. Small transfers of more recent records occur annually.
A box containing recordings of interviews from the Council's Broadcast Media Project on minicassette was discovered at the Mudd Library and added to the collection in 2015 [ML.2015.023].
No information about appraisal is available for this collection.
Accruals are expected from the Council on Foreign Relations on an annual basis.
Portions of the Council’s records from 1921-1951, include Conferences, Study Groups, Meetings, and the War and Peace Project, are also available on microfiche at Princeton’s Firestone Library [MICROFICHE 1637]. The creation of this microfiche was conducted between the University Publications of America and the Council on Foreign Relations and did not involve Princeton University. A guide is available, see Film B Uncataloged box for microfiche 1637 at Firestone Microforms Services (Film). Additionally, many of the Council’s reports are available in published form. Please consult the Princeton University Library online catalog for available published reports.
Portions of the Council’s audio records described in the Sound Recordings Series have been digitized as part on an ongoing project. Contact the library for additional details.
A paper version of the "Records of Groups Index," covering the years 1922-1973, is available at the Mudd Manuscript Library.
Researchers interested in the Council on Foreign Relations may also wish to consult the interview transcripts from Columbia University's Council on Foreign Relations Visual Oral History Project.
Information in the Organizational History section was gathered from material within the Council’s records (notably historical information from the Administration Series and Annual Reports from the Publications Series), as well as the Council on Foreign Relations’ website, www.cfr.org. Of special interest are the annual reports, located at http://www.cfr.org/about/annual_report/ and Peter Grouse’s Continuing the Inquiry: The Council on Foreign Relations from 1921-1996, located at http://www.cfr.org/about/history/cfr/.
Keller, Kenneth H.; Maxwell, Kenneth, 1941-.; Murphy, Richard W. (Richard William), 1929-.; Siegman, Henry.; Whittaker, Jennifer.; Economic history -- 20th century.; International relations -- 20th century.; World politics -- 20th century.; United States -- Foreign economic relations.; United States -- Foreign relations -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents).; Manuscripts.; Minutes.; Proceedings.; Records.; American politics and government; Cold War; Diplomacy; Public policy/20th century; World War II
- Subseries 3A: Administration, 1918-2001; 10.43 linear feet 25 boxes
  The Administration Subseries details the administrative work necessary to support the Study Groups of the Council. Subject files include records relating to programming, budget, staff files, and Studies Administration and Staff meeting records. The Miscellaneous files at the end of this subseries contain mainly memos and correspondence from the Study Group administration, but also lists, booklets, papers, and reports.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically thereunder, beginning with a group of "General" files and ending with "Miscellaneous" files.
  - General, 1975-1991; 3 folders
    - 1975-1976, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - 1984-1985, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - 1990-1991, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Groups, 1993; 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - African Program, 1985-1993; 3 folders
    - 1985-1987, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - 1988, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - 1989-1993, 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - African Development Project Funding, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - al-Turabi, Hassan Abdullah, Dinner Planning, 1992; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Annual William Diebold, Jr. Program on International Economics, 1986; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Arab Thought Forum, 1985-1988; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Asia Advisory Group, 1994; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Asia Project, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Asian Studies, 1990-1995; 2 folders
    - Correspondence Regarding Budget/Funding, 1993-1995; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Program Information, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Attendance Statistics, 1941-1952; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Authors/Honoraria, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Berlin Conference, 1994; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Bicentennial Projects, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Blum, Robert, Correspondence Regarding China Studies, 1963-1965; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Brazil Workshop, Planning, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Brown University Fellows, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Budget, 1978-1986; portions of 2 boxes
    - 1978-1983, 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - 1984-1986, 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Center for Global Energy Studies, 1992; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - China Series Promotion, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Chronological File, 1985 January-May; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Current Issue Review Groups, General, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Clough Study Groups, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Committee Co-optees, 1994; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Communications Committee, 1918-1919; 2 folders
    - 1918-1919, 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - 1919, 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Special Project on Foreign Leaders, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Conceptual Framework of American Foreign Policy, Staff Thoughts, 1968-1972; 2 folders
    - 1968-1970, 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - 1971-1972, 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Cooper, Robert, Meeting, Planning, 1992; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Council on United States-Italian Relations, 1994; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Critical Issues, 1987-1991; 3 folders
    - 1987-1988, 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Fred, Cambodia, 1991; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Greene, Fred, Philippines, 1991 August; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Department Meeting Notes, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Discussion Groups, 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Discussion Groups Proposed, 1965-1969; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - East-West Project, 1986-1993; portions of 2 boxes
    - 1986-1988, 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - 1986-1988, 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - 1992-1993, 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Service Institute, Senior Advanced Course, 1958-1959; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Friedlander, Saul, Possible Meeting, 1975; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Goldscheider, Calvin, 1991; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Gribney, Japan Project, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Haiti Panel, 1994; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Hauser Project on Regional Conflict, 1988-1992; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Hayes Manuscript on Congress and South America, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Hollerman Manuscript, 1986; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Ikle, Fred C, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Ideas Collected by Manning, Bayless, 1973; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - International Trade Project, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Israeli-Palestinian Questions, 1975; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - Japan Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc. (JAIF), Studies Funding, 1993-1997; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - Kahler, Miles, Correspondence and Paper, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Kipper, Judith, Middle East Forum, Planning, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Kipper, Judith, Middle East Forum, Planning, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Kissinger, Henry, Book Proposal, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Kissinger, Henry, Correspondence Regarding Atlantic Policy Studies, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Labor and U. S. Foreign Policy, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Latin American Correspondents, 1931-1936; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Latin America Program, 1973-1996; 6 folders
    - General, 1992; 1996; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1994 April 27; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Discussion Group on Latin America, 1973-1974; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Latin America/International Economy, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Latin America, the U. S. and New International Economic Order, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Latin American Regionalism, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Leffingwell Lecture, Obasanjo, General Olusegun, 1987; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Long Range Planning, 1981-1983; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Lowenthal, Abe ,Thank Yous to Members re: Ideas for Studies Program, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Media Project, 1994; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Meetings, Seminars, and Visits, 1963; 1978-1983; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Meetings and Seminars, 1983-1993; portions of 2 boxes
    - 1983-1985, 1 folder (Box 108, Folder 17)
    - 1986-1987, 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - 1988-1993, 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Memos, 1986-1994; 2 folders
    - 1986-1989, 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - 1991-1994, 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Middle East Demographics, 1991; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Minter, William, Case Study in the Societal Bases of Foreign Policy Formation, undated; 2 folders (Box 109, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Pamphlet Series, 1947; 1960; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Peacekeeping Project, 1994; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Pew Charitable Trusts, Global Security Project, 1992-1994; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Policy Options in Western Europe, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Participation Statistics, 1975-1983; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Participating Fellows, 1973; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Policies, 1921-1971; 7 folders
    - Administration, 1927-1965; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Committee on Future Research Program, 1937; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Committee to Study the Council's Program, 1947; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Confidentiality, 1971; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Gay Report on the Future of the Studies Program, 1944; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Short Review of Policy Changes, 1921-1951; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - Suggestions, 1960-1963; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Policy Books, 1960-1976; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Princeton Conference on Future Program of Studies, 1945; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Procedures, 1985-1990; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Procedures/Information, 1990-1996; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - Program Coordinating Committee, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Program Guides, 1995-2000; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Programming, 1973-1983; 3 folders
    - 1973-1974, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - 1977-1980, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - 1980-1983, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Program Planning, 1965-1993; 3 boxes (2 partial)
    - 1965-1973, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - 1973-1974, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 111, Folder 8 to 9)
    - 1975-1976, 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - 1975-1976, 1 folder (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 112, Folder 2 to 3)
    - 1987, 1 folder (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - 1988, 1 folder (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - 1988-1989, 1 folder (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - 1989-1990, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 113, Folder 2 to 3)
    - 1992-1993, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Program Proposals, 1966-1994; portions of 2 boxes
    - 1966-1970, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - 1971-1972, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - 1972-1973, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - 1972-1973, 1973-1974, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - 1973-1974, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - 1975-1976, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - 1974-1978, 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - 1994, 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Leeds, Roger, 1975; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Proposals for Studies Expansion, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Publication, Correspondence, 1991-1996; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Qualifications, Director of Studies, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Relations with Film, Radio, and Television, 1975-1977; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Relations with Members, 1971; 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Rules and Procedures, Impact, 1962-1973; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Root Lecture, Burns, Arthur, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Seminar, University of Maryland Foreign Policy Fellows, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Science and Technology Program, 1991-1993; 2 folders
    - Funding, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - Rosters, 1991-1993; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - Spain Symposium, Planning, 1993; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Special Projects, 1970-1978; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 14)
  - Special Studies, Shirer, William, The Rise and Fall of the Third Reich, Funding, 1958; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 15)
  - Staff, 1960-2001 April; portions of 2 boxes
    - General, 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - Aho, Michael, Papers, 1992 February-March; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 17)
    - Discussion Groups, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Future Staffing, 1960-1972; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Kupchan, Charles A., Draft Chapters, 2001 April; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Memo, 1971; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Memos re: Proposed Discussion Groups and Current Issues Review Groups, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Studies Staff Symposia, 1990-1993; 2 folders (Box 115, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Staff Files, 1960-1988; 3 boxes (2 partial)
    - A, 1960-1972; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 8)
    - B, 1968-1976; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Br-C, 1968-1980; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Ch-Cr, 1967-1974; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - D-H, 1965-1979; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - J-L, 1964-1972; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - L-M, 1967-1974; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - M, 1966; 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - M-N, 1966-1975; 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - O-S, 1968-1988; 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - U-V, Y, 1972-1977; 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1983; 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Staff Meetings, 1955-1989; 4 boxes (1 partial)
    - 1955-1958, 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - 1958-1960, 1 folder (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - 1960-1962, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - 1963-1966, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1969, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - 1969-1970, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - 1970-1971, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - 1971-1972, 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - 1972 January-June, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - 1972-1973 May, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - 1973-1975 February, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - 1975-1976 March, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - 1976-1977 February, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - 1977, 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - 1977-1978, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - 1978-1980, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - 1980-1981, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - 1982-1985, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - 1985-1986, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - 1987-1989, 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Stone, Roger, Manuscript, The Nature of Development, 1990-1991; 3 folders (Box 121, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Stone, Roger, Manuscript, "Global Economics and the Rural Third World", 1991; 1 folder (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Studies, Actual and Proposed, 1925-1984; 4 boxes (2 partial)
    - 1925-1940, 1 folder (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - 1941-1948, 1 folder (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - 1950-1958, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - 1958-1959, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - 1959-1960, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - 1961-1962, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - 1962-1963, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - 1963-1964, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - 1965-1966, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1967, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - 1967-1968, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - 1968-1969, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - 1969-1970, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - 1970-1971, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - 1971-1972, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - 1977-1978, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - 1977-1981, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - 1979-1984, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - 1981-1982, 1 folder (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - 1983-1984, 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Studies on Foreign Policy Pamphlets, 1953-1969; 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Study Groups, 1954-1992; portions of 2 boxes
    - 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - 1968-1973, 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Africa Study Groups, Miscellaneous Information, 1964-1992; 2 folders
      - 1964-1967, 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - 1987-1992, 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - American Attitudes Toward China, Proposals, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Defense of Middle East, Research Secretary Rustow, 1954-1955; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - European-American Project, 1983; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Financing Development: Japan's New Role, 1987; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - How the World Economy Has Changed, 1987; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - International Organization and Law Project, 1991-1992; 2 folders
      - Planning, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 5)
      - Study Group on United States Policies Towards the United Nations, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Middle East Study Groups, Miscellaneous Information, 1982-1991; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Population and United States Foreign Policy, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Soviet-American Relations, 1973; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Stepan, Alfred, 1974; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Suggested Topics for Study, 1956-1964; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Sustainable Development, Outline and Notes, 1993; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - Ukraine, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 13)
  - United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED), 1992; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 14)
  - United States-China Dialog, Planning, 1993-1994; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 15)
  - Vietnam S.E.A. Discussion, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 16)
  - Women's Foreign Policy Group, 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 125, Folder 17)
  - Wohlstetter, Albert, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 126, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Zagoria, Donald, Manuscript on Soviet Policy in Asia, 1988-1991; 1 folder (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1987; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    - 1956-1973, 1 folder (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - 1973, 1 folder (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 126, Folder 6 to 7)
    - 1975-1977, 1 folder (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - 1977-1979, 2 folders (Box 127, Folder 1 to 2)
    - 1979-1982, 1 folder (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - 1982-1983, 1 folder (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - 1984-1985, 1 folder (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - 1986-1987, 1 folder (Box 127, Folder 6)